# **NIKHIL SINGH**

www.nikhilsingh.me

## **PROFILE**

I've provided customer service for 7+ years: first representing patients, moving on to internal customer support as an analyst for Revenue Operations, and later as an IT analyst supporting the Operations team.

I currently represent business customers as a liaison to internal Compliance and Legal teams and am looking to apply my skills in a new industry.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**DaVita Kidney Care**, Malvern, PA Analyst, Setup Risk Management 1/2016 - Present

- Mitigate company risk by:
  - managing potential issues reported by internal customers
  - guarding patient privacy through responsible use of data
  - preserving confidentiality of ongoing legal investigations
  - working across teams to develop technical solutions to prevent breach of regulations
- Educate the Compliance and Legal teams on healthcare industry standards and serve as an interpreter to facilitate swifter, less complicated discourse for 10-15 requests each week
- Conduct data research and communicate findings for Medicaid audits, each involving 7,000-12,000 claims, to ensure leadership can speak intelligently and accurately about any financial discrepancies
- Streamline and document workflow processes and create custom SQL tables, queries, forms, and reports for the team

**DaVita Kidney Care**, Malvern, PA Applications Support Analyst, Information Technology 2/2012 - 12/2015

- Collaborated with Revenue Operations customers as a representative of IT, built on their research through SQL queries, and implemented creative solutions within the limitations of the electronic billing systems
- Taught myself to read and reproduce code for electronic claim files to verify accurate billing to high volume payers through an external clearinghouse

# **EDUCATION**

**BA, Economics**The University of Texas at Austin
December 2008

## **SKILLS**

- SQL
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft Access
- Microsoft SharePoint
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Friotosilo
   Adobe InDesign
- HTML
- CSS

# RECOGNITION

2017: Awards for exemplifying values of team and service excellence

2015: Award for IT guiding principle of teamwork

2012: Award for service excellence

2010: Recognized as teammate of the month for emphasis on process improvement

**DaVita Kidney Care**, Malvern, PA Payer Specialist, Revenue Operations 5/2011 - 12/2011

- Independently executed trend analyses and reporting on a monthly basis to improve efficiency within the billing infrastructure for 6 states and over 50 insurance payers
- Reduced monthly average outstanding customer support tickets from 100 to 30 over a period of 3 months by developing a more effective prioritization system

**DaVita Kidney Care**, Malvern, PA

6/2010 - 4/2011

Patient Account Representative, Revenue Operations

- Analyzed payment metrics to ensure that patients' insurance policies were reimbursing correctly, and if not, communicated with payer representatives to determine root causes

DaVita Kidney Care, Malvern, PA

2/2010 - 5/2010

Accounts Receivable Assistant, Revenue Operations

- Supported account representatives by completing billing adjustment projects and investigating issues with insurance payers
- Promoted within first 3 months

National Instruments, Austin, TX Intern, Investor Relations 1/2008 - 5/2008

 Analyzed competitors to determine how to better attract investors and sell-side analysts

# **ABOUT ME**

I can speak, read, and write Hindi

#### Likes:

- reading
- drawing
- wildlife trivia
- · comic books
- peanut butter

#### Dislikes:

- weak WiFi signal
- sour things